Guide to the Lesly Lempert Collection, 1987-1994.
Lempert, Lesly Collection
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
The Lesly Lempert Collection, 1987-1994.
6774
Lempert, Lesly
9 cubic feet.
Correspondence, Printed Materials, Publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Documentation from Israeli and Palestinian Human Rights Groups during the First Intifada (1987).
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Lesly Lempert, an American citizen with ongoing connections to the Jewish community in Ithaca, New York and to several American-based organizations working on human rights in the Israeli-administered territories, collected a number of publications relating to Palestinian Arab concerns and human-rights issues during the term of the First Intifada. The time range is generally, with several exceptions, from about 1987 to about 1994, i.e. the duration of the Intifada and its political and humanitarian consequences. The material in this collection was compiled chiefly during Lesly Lempert's twelve-year tenure as Executive Director of the American-Israeli Civil Liberties Coalition.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Documentation from Israeli and Palestinian Human Rights Groups during the First Intifada (1987). Series 1 contains sporadic, but often substantial, periodical holdings (chiefly English) from Palestinian Arab groups such as al-Haq, American and Israeli civil-liberties groups (e.g., B'Tselem) and several Israeli-Palestinian collaborative entities. Series 2 contains miscellaneous organizational and personal correspondence.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Lempert, Lesly.
Subjects:
Intifada, 1987-1993; Human rights--West Bank; Human rights--Gaza Strip; Intifada, 1987-1993; Human rights--West Bank; Human rights--Gaza Strip
Form and Genre Terms:
Periodicals; Correspondence
INFORMATION FOR USERS
HISTORICAL NOTE
In December 1987, the First Intifada erupted into a full-scale, multi-year, essentially nationalist uprising against two decades of Israeli occupation and administration of the West Bank (Judaea-Samaria) and the Gaza Strip. The uprising had multiple causes, including desperate living conditions among Palestinian Arabs, a pervasive sense of situational inferiority among these inhabitants, ineffective Arab political and military action and a number of Israeli political misperceptions and tactical errors. (For a methodical discussion of the genesis of the First Intifada, see Shalev, Aryeh. “Intifada.” Encyclopaedia Judaica, 2nd ed., vol. 9: 827-837 (electronic version accessible through the Cornell on-line catalogue, http://catalog.library.cornell.edu).
The uprising included a large number of riots, characterized by stone-throwing and the use of petrol bombs; and other acts of violence, including attacks on public transit. Palestinian Arab violence, sometimes homicidal, against both the Israel Defense Force and Israeli civilians occurred. The Israeli response was at least initially defective and uneven in tactical terms and thus produced more Palestinian Arab casualties than it might have otherwise. There were also “more instances of excesses by IDF soldiers,” according to Aryeh Shalev in the article cited, than there had been during past disturbances.
Books associated with the Lempert Collection have been integrated into the book collections of the Cornell University Library.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Periodicals
Series II. Correspondence
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Periodicals
  - Background Paper: On the Conditions of Lebanese & Palestinian Prisoners: Two Israeli Eyewitness Accounts, [1982?]; photocopy, 8 leaves (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Producer: ADC
    Volume/Number: 10
  - American Public Opinion and the Question of Palestine, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Volume/Number: 22
  - Urgent Appeal: Palestinian Prisoners Hunger Strike Into its Ninth Day to Protest Deteriorating Conditions and Treatment, October 5, 1992; photocopy, 2 leaves (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Producer: Ad-Hoc Committee for Palestinian Political Prisoners
  - Urgent Appeal to Release Ahmad Qatamesh Palestinian Writer & Community Activist, 1992; photocopy, 2 leaves (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Producer: Ad-Hoc Committee for the Release of Ahmad Qatamesh, Association of Israeli and Palestinian Physicians for Human Rights (AIPPHR)
  - April 17 Bulletin, October 22, 1995-March 15, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Producer: Alternative Information Center (AIC)
  - April 17: Magazine for Information and Support of Political Prisoners, August, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Volume/Number: 2/3
  - Article 74, November 11, 1991--September 10, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Producer: Alternative Information Center (AIC), Women's Human Rights Project, Palestinian Federation of Women's Action Committees
    Volume/Number: 1--6, 8--10
  - [Background Information], [?] (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - News from Within, June 23, 1987--August 8, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Volume/Number: 3.9--4.1, 4.8, 4.10, 5.2, 5.4--5.6, 6.1--6.7
  - News from Within, September 5, 1990--October 2, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Volume/Number: 6.8--7.10
  - News from Within, January 6, 1992--October/November 1992 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Volume/Number: 8.1--8.10/11
  - News from Within, November 1, 1992--September 5, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Volume/Number: 8.12--9.1, 9.4, 9.7--9.10
  - News from Within, October 5, 1993--December 1994 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Volume/Number: 9.10, 9.12--10.10, 10.12
  - News from Within, January 1995--July 1996 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Volume/Number: 11.1, 11.3, 11.6, 11.8, 11.10--11.11, 12.4--12.7
  - The Other Front, December 16, 1988--September 26, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Volume/Number: 16--17, 19--20, 23, 26, 28--29, 31--32, 34/35, 40, 43--46, 48, 50--53, 55--56, 61--62, 66--67, 69--76, 79, 81--87, 89--92, 94
  - The Other Front, September 26, 1990--November 21, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Volume/Number: 94, 97, 99, 102--104, 106, 108--112, 116--134, 138--140, 142, 144, 146--148
  - The Other Front, December 10, 1991--November 11, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Volume/Number: 150, 152--158, 160--178, 180--182, 184--188, 190--195
  - The Other Front, November 11, 1992--October 20, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Volume/Number: 195--206, 208--226, 228--229, 233--234, 236, 238/9--243
  - The Other Front, October 27, 1993--August 25, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Volume/Number: 244--252, 254--256, 258--263, 265, 267-- 287
  - The Other Front, September 5, 1994--October 15, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Volume/Number: 288--290, 292--299, 301, 304, 306--308, 310, 312, 332--333, 340--341
  - Palestine and the Other Israel: Alternative Directory of Progressive Groups and Institutions in Israel and the Occupied Territories, October 22, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - The Trap is Closing on Palestinian Jerusalemites (memorandum), February, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Producer: Alternative Information Center (AIC), Project for Palestinian Residency & Refugee Rights, (multiple authors)
  - Urgent Issues of Palestinian Residency in Jerusalem, October 28, 1993; photocopy, 2 leaves (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Urgent Issues of Palestinian Residency in Jerusalem, june, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Hebron Prison - A View from Inside: A Comprehensive Report on the Conditions in the Regular Services and the General Security Services' Interrogation Section: Based on a Prisoners' Report, July, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 22 A)
    Producer: Alternative Information Center (AIC), Mohammed Jaradat (Editor), Dr. Tikva Honig-Parnass (Editor)
  - Archive Collectin of THE OTHER ISRAEL: Newsletter of the Israeli Council for Israeli-Palestinian Peace, Issues 1-33, July 1983-September 1988, [1988] (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Producer: America-Israel Council for Israeli-Palestinian Peace
  - Israeli Peace Leaders and Academics Urge U.S. Housing Loan Assistance be Conditioned on Settlement Freeze, July 22, 1991; press release (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - From the Hebrew Press: Monthly Translations and Commentaries from Israel, April 1989--March 1990 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Producer: American Educational Trust, Israel Shahak (translator)
    Volume/Number: 1.4--1.9, 1.11--2.1, 2.3
  - From the Hebrew Press: Monthly Translations and Commentaries from Israel, May 1990--December 1990 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Volume/Number: 2.[5]--2.12
  - From the Hebrew Press: Monthly Translations and Commentaries from Israel, January 1991--July 1991 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    Volume/Number: 3.1--3.7
  - From the Hebrew Press: Monthly Translations and Commentaries from Israel, September 1991--December 1991 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Volume/Number: 3.9--3.12
  - From the Hebrew Press: Monthly Translations and Commentaries from Israel, January 1992--May 1992 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Volume/Number: 4.1--4.6
  - From the Hebrew Press: Monthly Translations and Commentaries from Israel, July 1992--January 1993 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    Volume/Number: 4.[7]--5.1
  - Construction in the Jewish Settlements in the Territories, 1993; photocopy, 4 leaves (Box 1, Folder 31)
    Producer: American Friends of RATZ
  - A Special Report: Curfew, [?] (Box 1, Folder 32)
    Producer: American-Israeli Civil Liberites Coalition
  - An American Jewish Appeal to Help Purchase Food and Medical Supplies for the Palestinian Community, [?]; typescript, 2 leaves (Box 1, Folder 33)
    Producer: American-Israeli Civil Liberites Coalition, (multiple organizations)
  - [Background Information], [?] (Box 1, Folder 34)
    Producer: American-Israeli Civil Liberties Coalition
  - (Background Information): Introduction to the Coalition, typescript, 5 leaves (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - (Background Information): The Coalition: Introduction, 2 versions (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - (Background Information): Introduction: the Coalition and Kol Koreh, photocopy, 5 leaves (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - (Background Information): Statement of Purpose, April, 1984; 2 versions (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - The Coalition and Kol Koreh, [post 1986]; photocopy, 7 leaves (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Coalition Statement on the Problem of Reunification of Palestinian Families in the Occupied Territories, January 31, 1991; photocopy, 3 leaves (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Facts About Civil Liberties in Israel, March 1, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - (On Back): U.S. Sate Department Reports on Israel's Human Rights Record in the Occupied Territories, March 1, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    Producer: Focus
  - L.A. Zionists Gather to Defend Arab, Christian and Secular Rights, October 11, 1983; press release, typescript, 2 leaves (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Newsletter, November/December 1986--Autumn 1987 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    Volume/Number: 6.3, 7.1
  - Newsletter, 1982, 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    Volume/Number: 1.1, 3.3, 4.1-2, 5.1-2, 6.1
  - News Update, September, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Newspaper, Summer 1990--Summer 1994 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    Volume/Number: 10.2, 11.1, 12. 1, 13.2, 14.2, 15.1
  - A Land Divided, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    Producer: American-Israeli Civil Liberties Coalition, David Shipler
  - Supreme Court Sitting in Jerusalem (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - An American Jewish Appeal for Food & Medical Supplies for the West Bank & Gaza, [1991?] (Box 1, Folder 40 A)
    Producer: American-Israeli Civil Liberties Coalition, America-Israel Council for Israeli-Palestinian Peace, International Jewish Peace Union (et al)
  - From the Battlefield to the Negotiating Table: A compilation of press clippings featuring Peace Now and Americans for Peace Now, October 1990--1992 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    Producer: Americans for Peace Now
  - The Zionist Movement Revisited: A Jewish Currents Reprint, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 41 A)
    Producer: Louis Harp, Jewish Currents
    Volume/Number: 11
  - Algeria: Deteriorating Human Rights Under the State of Emergency (country profile), March, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    Producer: Amnesty International
  - Amnesty Action, Summer/Fall 1992 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Amnesty International's Biennial Council in Yokohama: Tough Stand Against Killings, Hostage-Taking by Violent Groups, September 7, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Egypt (country profiles), January 1992--September 1994 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - (Egypt): Security Police Detentions Undermine the Rule of Law, January, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - (Egypt): Grave Human Rights Abuses Amid Political Violence, May, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - (Egypt): Military Trials of Civilians: A Catalog of Human Rights Violations, October, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - (Egypt): Human Rights Defenders Under Threat, September, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Focus: Against their will: Rape and Sexual Abuse in Custody, February, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Iran: Imprisonment, Torture, and Execution of Political Opponents (country profile), January, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Iraq (country profiles), February 1993--September 1993 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - (Iraq): Written statement to the 49th Session of the United Nations Commission on Human Rights, February, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - (Iraq): "Disappearance" of Shi'a clerics and students, April, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - (Iraq): Secret detention of Kuwaitis and third-country nationals, September, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Israel and the Occupied Territories: Administrative Detention: Dr. Rabah Hasan 'Abd al-'Aziz Mohanna, June 2, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Israel and the Occupied Territories: Amnesty International Appeals for an End to Arbitrary Killings, December 2, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Israel and the Occupied Territories: Medical Letter Writing Action, December 16, 1991--November 26, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - (Medical Letter Writing Action): Dr. Rabah Hasan 'Abd al-'Aziz Mohanna, December 16, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - (Medical Letter Writing Action): Avraham Marcus Klingberg, November 26, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Israel and the Occupied Territories (country profiles), June 1998--August 1993 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - (Israel and the Occupied Territories): The Misues of Tear Gas by Israeli Army Personnel in the Israeli Occupied Territories, June, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - (Israel and the Occupied Territories): The Use of Live Ammunition by Members of the Israel Defence Force, June, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - (Israel and the Occupied Territories): Excessive Force: Beatings to Maintain Law and Order, August, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - (Israel and the Occupied Territories): Update to the Use of Live Ammunition by Members of the Israeli Defence Force, September, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - (Israel and the Occupied Territories): Conscientious Objection, October 18, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - (Israel and the Occupied Territories): Administrative Detention During the Palestinian Intifada, June, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - (Israel and the Occupied Territories): Update to Administrative Detention During the Palestinian Intifada, November, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - (Israel and the Occupied Territories): The Military Justice System in the Occupied Territories: Detention, Interrogation and Trial Procedures, July, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - (Israel and the Occupied Territories): Amnesty International's response to the comments of the Israeli Ministry of Justice on the Amnesty International Reports 1990 and 1991, October, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - (Israel and the Occupied Territories): Mordechai Vanunu: Solitary confinement as cruel, inhuman, or degrading treatment, October, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - (Israel and the Occupied Territories): Druze conscientious objectors to military service, November, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - (Israel and the Occupied Territories): Oral Statement to the United Nations Commission on Human Rights on the Israeli Occupied Territories, January, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - (Israel and the Occupied Territories): Fear of torture or ill-treatment, March, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - (Israel and the Occupied Territories): David Ish Shalom-prisoner of conscience, May, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - (Israel and the Occupied Territories): Husnia 'Abd al-Qader-administrative detention, June, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - (Israel and the Occupied Territories): Nayef 'Ali Nayef Sweitat-prisoner of conscience, June, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - (Israel and the Occupied Territories): Oral Statement to the United Nations Commission on Human Rights on the Israeli Occupied Territories, February, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - (Israel and the Occupied Territories): Killings by Israeli Forces: an upsurge in 1993: Cases for Appeals, July, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - (Israel and the Occupied Territories): Doctors and interrogation practices: The case of Nader Qumsieh, August, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Israel and the Occupied Territories (News Release), June 1988--October 5, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - (Israel and the Occupied Territories): Odds Stacked Against Fair Trials for Palestinians, July 30, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - (Israel and the Occupied Territories): Amnesty International Concerned about Deportation Orders Against Palestinians, January 8, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - (Israel and the Occupied Territories): Amnesty International Concerned about Secret Detentions in Israel, January 22, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - (Israel and the Occupied Territories): Amnesty International Calls for Urgent Measures Against Torture and Ill-treatment after Death of Detainee, Februry 12, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - (Israel and the Occupied Territories): Amnesty International Condemns Hostage-Taking of Israeli Police Officer and Seeks Assurances for Palestinian Detainees, December 15, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - (Israel and the Occupied Territories): Amnesty International Strongly Condemns the Killing of Israeli Hostage, Calls on Israel to Stop the Deportation of Palestinian Detainees, December 17, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - (Israel and the Occupied Territories): Amnesty International Welcomes Repeal of Law, January 29, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - (Israel and the Occupied Territories): Concerns about Treatment of Detainees, March 3, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - (Israel and the Occupied Territories): Amnesty International Concerned about House Destructions, March 30, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - (Israel and the Occupied Territories): Death in Custody, May 7, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - (Israel and the Occupied Territories): Amnesty International Extremely Concerned at the Situation in the Occupied Gaza Strip, May 27, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - (Israel and the Occupied Territories): Amnesty International Calls for Strong Human Rights Safeguards to be Included into Peace Settlement, September 13, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - (Israel and the Occupied Territories): Chairman Arafat Affirms Palestine Liberation Organization Commitment to Human Rights, October 5, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Israel/South Lebanon: Medical Concern: More than 400 Palestinians, December 31, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Israel/South Lebanon (country profiles), May 1992--May 6, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - (Israel/South Lebanon): The Khiam detainees: torture and ill-treatment (Country Profile), May, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - (Israel/South Lebanon): Khiam Detainees Tortured and Isolated (News Release), May 6, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Jordan, September 17, 1991--August 18, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - (Jordan): Amnesty International Welcomes Royal Pardon but Calls for Right of Appeal to Ensure Fair Trial, November 20, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - (Jordan): Incommunicado detention of political prisoners (country profile), June, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - (Jordan): Amnesty International Regret Over Executions, August 18, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Kuwait: AI Fears Imminent Executinos, Concerned that Defendants in Bush Assassination Case Will Not Get Fair Trial, July 1, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Lebanon: Update on the Case of Ron Arad, an Israeli Soldier Missing in Lebanon Since October 1986, October 11, 1993; news release (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Libya, June, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - (Libya): Amnesty International's prisoner concerns in the light of recent legal reforms (country profile), June, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - (Libya): Human Rights Situation in Libya Deteriorates after Failure of Reforms, Amnesty International Says, June 26, 1991; news release (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Morocco (country profiles), July 1991--February 1993 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - (Morocco): Amnesty International's concerns February-June 1991, July, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - (Morocco): Continued Detention of Three Brothers Who "Disappeared" in 1973, December 23, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - (Morocco): Prisoners of Conscience Released After "Disappearing" 18 Years Ago, January 9, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - (Morocco): Long-term "Disappearances" of Trade Unionists, April, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - (Morocco): Continuing arrests, "disappearances" and restrictions on freedom of expression and movement in Western Sahara, February, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Newsletter, January, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    Volume/Number: 1.1
  - Saudi Arabia (country profiles), May 15, 1993--May 10, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - (Saudi Arabia): An upsurge in public executions, May 15, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - (Saudi Arabia): Christians and Shi'a Muslims Suffer Persecution, September 14, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - (Saudi Arabia): Unwelcome "guests": The plight of Iraqi refugees, May 10, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Syria, July, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - (Syria): Political Prisoners Still Detained and Tortured Despite Mass Releases (country profile), July 22, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - (Syria): Indefinite Political Imprisonment: Long-term detention and torture of political prisoners, July, 1992; news release (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Trade Unionists Action: 1992, February, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Tunisia (country profiles), October 1991--June 1993 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - (Tunisia): Deaths in custody during garde à vue detention, October, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - (Tunisia): Prolonged Incommunicado Detention and Torture, March, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - (Tunisia): Women victims of harassment, torture and imprisonment, June, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Urgent Action, May 17, 1991--May 3, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - World Conference on Human Rights: Facing Up to the Failures: Proposals for Improving the Protection of Human Rights by the United Nations, December, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Yemen, May 1992--September 1, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - (Yemen): Mansur Rajih: Prisoner of conscience under sentence of death (country profile), May, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - (Yemen): Unlawful detention and unfair trials of members of the former National Democratic Front (country profile), August 26, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - (Yemen): Amnesty International Calls on Both Sides to Respect Human Rights, May 10, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - (Yemen): Human rights concerns following recent armed conflict (country profile), September 1, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Torture in the Eighties: An Amnesty International Report, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 68 A)
  - Notes on the News, August/September 1994 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    Producer: Arab American Institute
  - Issues: Crisis in the Gulf, September/October 1990 (Box 2, Folder 69 A)
    Volume/Number: 28
  - Book Review: The Legal Status of the Arabs in Israel, 1991; photocopy, 3 pages (Box 2, Folder 70)
    Producer: Arab Association for Human Rights, David Kretzmer
  - Discrimination in Education Against the Arab Palestinians in Israel, April, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    Producer: Arab Association for Human Rights
  - Land in Arab Hands Before and After the Establishment of Israel, kmsq (Examples), [?] (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Press Release, February 26 [?]--February 28, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - World Conference on Human Rights, June, 1993; photocopy, 4 leaves (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - (World Conference on Human Rights): Palestinians Inside Israel: The "Uprooted People", June, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - (World Conference on Human Rights): Palestinians Inside Israel: Discrimination in Numbers, June, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 74)